Hello.
I'm Teacher Wang Shuyi.
Today, let's talk about how we can use Agent Skills to help with education.
So, some of you have been telling me...
Hey, Mr. Wang, long time no see!
Where have you been?
Well, here's the thing.
So, this semester, I've been competing in the Teaching and Innovation Contest.
So I've been super busy preparing for the competition lately.
so I haven't been showing up much.
So, the other day, a few of my online friends came over to Tianjin.
and we all got together for a chat.
And they were saying, um, they're really looking forward to my videos.
So I said, "Alright then."
Alright, let's have a seat then.
Because I was actually in the middle of preparing for this teaching innovation competition.
I've had quite a bit of time to reflect and gather some insights.
So today, let's dive in and I'll show you what's possible with some of the latest technologies.
So, what kind of help can these agent skills actually provide for teaching and learning right now?
So, today, I'm going to walk you through two main scenarios.
The first one is for creating animations.
The other is a personalized teaching assistant.
Alright.
See? Pretty useful, right?
So, let's start with the whole animation thing.
So, the one I want to recommend here is HAGEN.
Alright,
This is a pretty famous AI company in the video creation space.
So, what's the new thing they've come out with?
It's called Hyper Frames.
So, this is a whole series of skills.
So, as you can see, they've got these 'skills' right here.
It's actually a whole series of...
And I really like the stuff it creates.
Alright, so next, let's talk about my own teaching scenarios.
So, this scenario is for a machine learning course.
So, for this course...
Every year, when I get to these parts of the course that really need animations to be properly explained,
Especially when we get to deep learning, right?
this, uh, downhill slope...
You know, this kind of stuff.
When you're explaining this slope,
all that stuff.
Of course, the more vividly I can present it, the better.
But before, it was actually quite a hassle.
I could only find some ready-made demos made by others and just present them.
But when it comes to what you actually need,
there's still a huge gap.
So, in this scenario, you can see what I'm doing.
So, I'm using a deep neural network to classify the Titanic dataset.
Don't ask me why.
So why use a deep neural network to classify the Titanic dataset, you ask?
This is mainly for explanation and demonstration purposes.
I'm not saying this is the right way to do it,
So, let's take a look at what happens during this process.
Alright, so about that skill we were just talking about...
or rather, this whole series of skills.
So, how exactly can it help us when it comes to creating animations?
Alright, let me show you a couple of examples of what it can do.
I won't show you too many examples.
The first one is forward propagation.
This explains the whole process, from the input all the way to the output.
And of course, this output needs to be corrected, right?
So, what does that process actually look like?
Normally, you'd have to draw this all out on the blackboard.
And then, you explain this whole process to them.
But writing on the blackboard is pretty inefficient.
But if you use a pre-made video, it might not be the exact one you want to show for this specific topic.
So, this dataset...
and the students are just left completely baffled.
But with this 'skill' we've been talking about,
Let's take a look at how it works.
So, how exactly does a DNN do its calculations?
Input the seven Titanic features for a passenger.
Female, 28 years old, in first class.
All by herself.
The fare was 82.17 pounds.
Upload the categorical features from Southampton.
First, it goes through the hidden layer.
into smaller vectors and continuous features.
And put them together.
into the first hidden layer.
32 neurons.
Each one performs a weighted sum of all the inputs, plus a bias term.
and then passed through the ReLU activation.
For instance, let's take one neuron and calculate its value, which comes out to 11.37.
These 32 parallel computations then produce a 32-dimensional vector.
and into the second layer.
Then, 16 neurons repeat the process in the final layer.
The two outputs are then passed through the softmax function to become probabilities for the two classes.
Probability of survival: 0.9.
and 0.09 for perishing.
We take the higher probability as the survival prediction.
And that's one complete forward propagation.
So, what do you think of this effect?
Alright then.
And the second part is the optimization function.
So, when we need it to correct and optimize,
So, what are the functions that can help it learn faster and better?
Let's take a look at this segment of the same Titanic loss landscape.
Three balls start from the same point to roll down the hill.
SGD only looks at the current gradient path.
It's really shaky.
and slowly reaches the bottom.
Momentum adds inertia from the previous direction of travel.
and keeps a bit of its momentum.
It's noticeably faster at traversing flat regions.
ADAM is the smartest one.
It adaptively estimates the first and second-order moments independently for each dimension, which adjusts the learning rate.
And it turns out, ADAM converges to the bottom of the valley the fastest.
SGD is the slowest.
For most tabular tasks, like the Titanic dataset,
So just using ADAM or ADAMW saves a lot of trouble.
So, if we were to introduce it this way,
Wouldn't it be easier for students to grasp these concepts more intuitively?
complex concepts, right?
And the contrast is incredibly clear and striking.
So, what you're seeing isn't actually a video.
So, you might be thinking, 'Wait, isn't this just a video?'
But it's not a video.
It's actually HTML combined with audio.
Of course, the audio here is a clone of my own voice.
And I'm sure you've already noticed.
This isn't my natural voice.
But I gotta say, it sounds pretty natural and smooth, though.
So, what's the upside to all this?
You might be thinking, 'Well, doesn't it just look like an animated video anyway?'
Here's the thing.
The real benefit comes when you need to make changes.
In the past, when we had to render this kind of video,
And that step is incredibly time-consuming.
So, if I find a problem here,
Sometimes you just couldn't be bothered to fix it.
Because the cost of making changes was just too high.
The mental load is just too heavy.
But now, making changes is incredibly simple.
So, right here, I just tell it,
So, I'm telling it, 'Look, there are two layers here.'
It was originally just two hundred and one hundred.
But you just read it out as 201,000.
You'd say, 'Wait, that's not right.'
Alright, go ahead and fix this number for me.
So I asked it to fix it.
And then, it starts to reflect on it.
So, what did the script I wrote back then actually look like?
And then it realizes, 'Oh, wait, I have 200, comma, 100 here.'
Following the English way of saying it,
So of course, that would be two hundred thousand one hundred.
So, it's telling me, 'Alright, it looks like I need to make a change here.'
So, next, he's just going to modify the introduction right here.
And then it'll regenerate the MP3 for this part.
And it's done in a flash.
And once it's done, it automatically inserts it right in.
So I'll just regenerate it right here.
Everything's working perfectly.
In the past, if you wanted to render a video like this,
Animating something this complex was just unthinkable.
Yeah, that would have taken a while to render, for sure.
So, what's the second benefit?
The second benefit is personalization.
Now, pay attention.
Everything I've just demonstrated,
all revolved around the Titanic dataset.
But in reality, when you see other people's introductions out there,
using this deep neural network for classification,
all of its relevant metrics and so on,
or its various features and capabilities.
It's not going to limit you to just
So, for the Titanic dataset we're using here,
So, it can explain things by incorporating your specific data.
And this, in my opinion, is incredibly useful.
This helps students stay engaged and not get distracted.
Right?
Alright, so let's move on to the second one.
A personalized teaching assistant.
And this next one, I think, is even more interesting.
Well, this is actually a 'skill' I developed earlier.
This skill...
I really polished it up back then.
And why is that?
Because this was actually from when I went to Peking University to give a lecture in mid-April.
I made it for the students in the Department of Information Management at Peking University.
So, what's it for?
I was basically there to show them
This is kind of like the concept of an AI red team.
So, you see, you're all learning the relevant skills for this subject.
So, what I'm going to do here is, fundamentally,
equipped with the skills of a data analyst.
It can be combined with a domain expert.
to provide you with data analysis services.
And then, you can share your own insights with it.
and it can give you more reliable results.
It will determine the various boundaries on its own.
It'll even reflect on its own work, you know?
So, does this whole data analysis process make sense?
And finally, it gives you a confidence score.
and ask you to decide whether you can sign off on a data analysis report.
So, this is the skill I shared with everyone back then.
Alright, so let's take a look at the actual results from running it.
So, once you've added this skill to your own agent,
It can perform all sorts of analyses.
And keep in mind, all this analysis is grounded in real professional expertise.
Yeah, and at the time, we were also using the Titanic dataset.
It will give you some conclusions.
It will even point out the things that you can't conclusively say, giving you all the caveats.
This includes the distinction between correlation and causation, right?
This particular shipwreck was unique.
Because, in and of itself,
And on the ship, there was a certain amount of time, right?
From the moment it struck the iceberg to the time it sank,
So, there are still social norms at play in this situation.
So you can't just extrapolate from it, right?
And finally, I've also got some suggestions like these for teaching scenarios.
This is what I shared with the students at Peking University back then.
So, I was thinking,
So, what can I do to iterate on this?
and build upon that foundation.
I wanted it to help a student better learn the machine learning course.
So, why am I doing this?
It's because, for my machine learning course this semester...
Well, you could say it's changed a lot.
I had my students use an AI agent to assist them.
This kind of programming process...
This means that a huge amount of time we used to spend...
that we would have spent on writing code,
So now, all that time can be saved.
However, some students might develop a kind of cognitive dependency or offload their thinking entirely.
I mean, what the AI produces is pretty good.
So I'll just turn that in directly.
But that's not okay.
So, how do I do it?
Here, let me show you.
So, let me show you the effect I've got here.
So in here, if you say, 'machine learning TA'...
So, you're just calling this 'skill'.
Classifying Titanic with a DNN.
It doesn't just go straight from start to finish.
It directly gives you the final analysis result, end-to-end.
Generating code and a report.
He hands it to you,
Here you go.
Hand it over to the teacher.
That's not what it does.
So, what does it do?
First, it goes and finds the data.
And then, it performs some preparatory tasks.
After that,
He does one thing,
For every key step,
and for each one, it sets up a corresponding question right here.
He says, 'I'm going to set this task up as a binary classification prediction model.'
So, what do you think the basis for that decision is?
And it's going to ask you to answer for each part.
So, this process of answering is actually about the bigger picture,
What is it trying to do?
So you get a basic understanding.
And this is where your understanding of the key concepts gets put to the test.
See, I'll answer it right here.
So, I'm saying the target variable is 'survive'.
So, there are two possibilities, right?
One is 'yes',
and the other is NO, right?
And then, it says the student's answer has grasped the key point.
Right, so this is a binary classification, correct?
It didn't say 'regression' or anything like that, but the answer is correct.
So, to move things forward, I'll have it start processing from the beginning.
and starts moving backward.
After a moment,
After analyzing what these different features represent,
Then it paused again and asked me,
So,
I pointed out that some fields had missing values.
So, what type of missing data do you think this is?
So, for the sake of time,
So I won't walk you through my entire thought process here.
So, let's take a look at the final output.
So, what I've defined in this Skill is...
I had it generate three things for me.
If you've ever done any data science analysis before,
It can generate that for you.
The whole thing, including your comments and code, is all seamlessly integrated.
And it's executable.
Alright, let's take a look. This is opened up in Visual Studio Code.
And you'll see, the steps are laid out very clearly.
and the key findings, which are the results of running the code at each step.
And all the sticking points along the way.
Step by step.
So, it's asking you questions, right?
All of this is right here.
And on top of that, it even includes a final reflection section.
I think what this actually does is incredibly well done.
And it's not just that.
And it's not just a report, it's an executable one.
So, what's next?
It generates a personalized learning report, just for you.
This isn't for an AI to read.
It's not for the computer.
This is for you to read.
And in here, it'll give you a task summary.
So, what have we done?
Checkpoint.
What questions did I ask?
And for each of these steps, there are specific knowledge points you need to master.
How did you do?
And I'll send you the corresponding attachments.
And then there's this part over here.
And you can actually share this with your teacher.
It can build a complete profile of your learning journey.
Plus, it even awards you points for in-class activities.
And it can provide all of that right here.
And that's not all.
Plus, it generates a personalized tutorial for you.
So, what is this?
Based on the questions you answered in here,
I intentionally left some tricky spots in there.
It's not that I don't know how, you know.
I mean, I've been teaching this course for a long time.
So I'm just pretending to be a student here.
He hasn't quite grasped it yet.
And then, you'll run into some sticking points and incorrect answers.
So, it will then provide you with an explanation.
And then, it'll give you the corresponding code.
and even provide you with targeted exercises.
So, what do you think of this? Pretty cool, right?
So that's the overall effect.
So, I'm going to share it with you as well.
So this is a QR code.
Inside, you'll find its ZIP file.
You can go ahead and install it on your client.
For my class demos, I use the domestic version of Tree.
Of course, you can use other tools as well.
Things like, you know, HERMES.
Cloud Code works too.
Alright, so let's do a quick recap of the technological advancements.
And just like that, it's right in front of us, advancing at lightning speed.
A lot of things that were impossible just yesterday,
today, it's already possible.
So, teachers are being empowered.
But we need to seize these opportunities.
Sometimes, when these things come along,
and you turn a blind eye,
and you'll just miss out on a golden opportunity.
So, what's even more important than that?
I think we should be empowering our students.
So, take a look at the Skill I just created.
I think this actually empowers the students.
In and of itself,
So, what exactly is a Skill file?
It's essentially an interaction between you and the AI.
You take some of the really noteworthy points,
You've taught the AI.
And just like that, the AI gets it.
So, once your students get this thing,
And it's customizable.
They can customize it based on their own needs,
They can use natural language to add, modify, or delete things on it.
So, this gives them something that's completely personalized.
a Skill like this.
And you should never underestimate students' creativity and adaptability.
So, for the Teaching Innovation Competition this semester,
I've made quite a few changes to my classes.
One of these was having students create their own 'skills'.
in a single class.
And out of that, only 15 minutes were dedicated to this specific module.
So, my students...
My students, over a dozen groups of them,
They each created their own modules across four main categories.
Some of them include, uh, the things they've created...
So, these are the kinds of skills that can whip up some recipes.
I find this really fascinating.
So, once students have their own skill,
So, what they're actually running right now is their very own agent.
So, they can use this to tackle their own problems.
And they can even apply this knowledge to other situations.
and extend it to different courses.
across different subjects.
And I think this is also about guiding students in the AI era,
a path to better adapt and thrive.
And this is especially true when we keep talking about personalized learning.
So, what does personalization really mean?
All students using one single agent.
That's not what personalization is.
Every student has their own unique agent.
and it runs a unique skill that's been customized specifically for them.
So, this kind of learning...
is what I think can truly be called personalized learning.
So, that's what I wanted to share with you today.
I hope this will be helpful for both your teaching and your learning.
Alright, before you go, don't forget to follow my official account.
Hey, it's Teacher Wang Shuyi from Bilibili! Don't forget to like, comment, and share!
I'm Teacher Wang Shuyi.
See you next time!